lalasavesyoumoney.com 2018-06-24

# Privacy Policy

Updated: 29 May 2018 

The operator of myiyo.com, mo’web GmbH, Mertensgasse 12, 40213. Düsseldorf, Germany, represented by managing director Herbert Höckel (info@mo-web.net), is responsible for this website. "myiyo" below therefore refers to the operator, mo’web GmbH. 

Contact the data protection officer at: datenschutzbeauftragter@mo-web.net 

By voluntarily registering with myiyo, you consent to myiyo processing your personal data in the context described below. If the processing of your data is not necessary for the performance of the Terms of Use or to comply with a statutory requirement, we only process your data on the basis of your consent. You may at any time withdraw your consent by deleting your account via the account settings or by sending a request to delete your account to contact.en@myiyo.com.  
Whether or not you are a member, we process the IP addresses and browser data of all visitors to this website to protect our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) GDPR). We have a legitimate interest in preventing misuse of the website and analysing the data to improve our service. 

myiyo respects and protects the rights of users relating to their personal data under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

Professional guidelines - myiyo is a service provided by mo’web GmbH, which is listed as a company in the ESOMAR Directory. Mr. Herbert Höckel, Managing Partner of mo’web, is an individual member of ESOMAR. ESOMAR publishes clear guidelines on professional ethics in market research (ICC/ESOMAR International Code of Marketing and Social Research Practice). mo’web is also a member of the BVM (Berufsverband Deutscher Markt- und Sozialforscher e.V.) and the DGOF (Deutsche Gesellschaft für Online-Forschung e.V.), so that it also follows strict guidelines on using addresses for marketing and social research. 

##  The purpose of this website and related data processing: 

myiyo collects and processes personal data for the purpose of carrying out market research surveys and opinion polls. Users who want to volunteer to take part in our surveys can register on myiyo.com and are then invited to participate in surveys by email or via the website. By participating in surveys, users collect points that they can subsequently convert into money.  
To add value for our users, myiyo has a range of social networking features that users can choose to use to communicate with other users. 

##  Personal data that is processed: 

When registering on myiyo, every user of myiyo must specify his or her first and last name, email address, password, gender, date of birth, country and employment status. In addition to these mandatory details, every user can subsequently make a number of voluntary statements in his or her profile questionnaire. The user can provide his/her address and answer various questions about his/her education, profession, household, travel, consumption of goods and services, Internet, computer, smartphone and transport. The additional information is used to narrow down the users who are eligible for surveys more effectively. We only process the personal data of our users for the purposes described above. 

Other data is collected from users in the course of regular surveys. Participation in individual surveys is voluntary, as is the disclosure of information in the surveys. We keep the identity of participants secret from our customers. 

We process our users' IP addresses for security purposes and to prevent a member with multiple accounts taking part in a survey multiple times. 

Users can publish their own posts and photos on the website if they choose to use our social networking features. Our privacy settings allow users to adjust what groups of people can view their content and personal information. 

When the contact form is used, we process the provided name and email address for contact purposes. 

##  Cookies & tracking 

We use cookies to store user preferences and to keep users logged in. We also use cookies to recognise users again for security purposes because we need to make sure that the same user cannot participate in the same survey multiple times.  
To track the origin of users who access myiyo via a link from certain advertising partners, we also record this information in a cookie so that we can pay the applicable advertising partner if a visitor completes registration.  
We store cookies for a period of one month.  
To enhance the effectiveness and reach of our website, in particular for marketing purposes, we use Google Analytics to collect and analyse visitor data. See below for details. 

##  Disclosure of personal data 

Our users' personal data is only disclosed to other parties for the purposes described above and only to the extent permitted by law, as allowed under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).  
We use service providers for web hosting and to send emails. We also use payment service providers (such as PayPal) and have to send our payment service providers the recipient's email address to be able to complete payments. Using these service providers is necessary to provide the myiyo service. To protect the data of our users, we only use service providers that either have their registered place of business in the EU or have their registered place of business in the United States and offer protection under the EU-US Privacy Shield Program. 

##  Duration of retention 

The personal data is not stored longer than necessary for the purposes described above. 

##  Rights of the user 

Users have the following rights regarding their personal data that is processed by us: 

  * **Right of access** to information about what personal data is processed and with whom the data is shared.
  * **Right to rectification** of the data
  * **Right to erasure** of the data (right to be forgotten)
  * **Right to restriction** of processing
  * **Right to object** to processing
  * **Right to data portability**
  * **Right to lodge a complaint** with the competent supervisory authority

Visitors use this website and provide personal data when using it, on a voluntary basis. 

##  Additional information about Google Analytics 

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; "Google"). This includes Universal Analytics, which makes it possible to link data, sessions and interactions across multiple devices to a pseudonymous user ID and therefore to analyse a user's activities across devices. 

Google Analytics uses cookies, which are text files that are stored on your computer to help analyse your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually sent to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, if IP anonymisation is enabled on this website, your IP address will first be truncated by Google within the Member States of the European Union or other parties to the agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transferred to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. The IP address sent by your browser for Google Analytics is not combined with other Google data. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to analyse your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide other services associated with website activity and Internet use for the website operator. We have a legitimate interest in data processing for these purposes. The legal basis for the use of Google Analytics is Section 15, para. 3 of the German Telemedia Act (TMG) and Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR. The data sent by us and linked to cookies, user identifiers (e.g. user ID) or advertising IDs is automatically deleted after 14 months. Once the applicable data retention period has passed, data is automatically deleted once a month. For more information about terms of use and privacy, please visit [http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/en.html](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/en.html) or <https://policies.google.com/?hl=en>. 

You can prevent cookies from being stored by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser. However, please note that by doing so you may not be able to use all the features of this website. You can also prevent the data generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) from being passed to Google and being processed by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available at the following link: [Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). Opt-out cookies prevent your data being collected when you visit this website in the future. To prevent data being collected by Universal Analytics across multiple devices, you must opt out on all the systems you are using. You can set the opt-out cookie by clicking here: Disable Google Analytics 

##  Additional information regarding Google reCAPTCHA 

We use the Google reCAPTCHA service (from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA) to verify and prevent interactions on our website through automated access. 

This service processes, in addition to the visited web page, the IP address, and a variety of other browser information to determine if a real person or a bot is behind the call. The legal basis for the use of this service is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. Our legitimate interest lies in the security of our service as well as the defense against unwanted, automated access in the form of spam or hacker attacks. 

##  Additional information about the vouchers from our partner, Sovendus GmbH 

When interviews fail, we offer some of our users a voucher from our partner Sovendus GmbH (Moltkestr. 11, 76133 Karlsruhe) to say sorry. After a user clicks on the link to the offer, data is transferred to Sovendus. We transfer a randomly generated session hash as well as the IP address at this time, so that Sovendus can check and provide the voucher. Sovendus only uses the IP address for security purposes and this is usually anonymised after seven days. We do not store the hash we generate and we also cannot use it to identify the user. For further information about the processing of your data by Sovendus, see the online Data Protection Notice at www.sovendus.de/datenschutz.
